Guide to the New-York Historical Society Museum Department Records 1765, 1830-2018 NYHS-RG 20
New-York Historical Society
- Series VI. Object Images, 1765, circa 1864-circa 1990; 23.96 Linear feet in 23 document boxes and cartons, and 13 small boxes of slides
  - Subseries VI.A. Image Files, 1765, circa 1864-circa 1990; 8.25 Linear feet
    - 1941.640 - 1944.392 to .428 (Offsite-box 170, Folder -)
      Includes restoration notes (1941.640, 1941.725, 1944.17); correspondence/notes (1941.1178, 1942.323, 1942.351, 1943.168, 1943.388, 1944.72, 1944.73, 1944.150, 1944.151, 1944.357, 1944.359); negatives/transparencies (1941.1210, 1942.323, 1942.324, 1942.356, 1942.357). Includes an attribution note from 1898 (1943.388).
    - 1945.2 - 1947.188 (Offsite-box 171, Folder -)
      Includes restoration notes (1925.5, 1925.14); correspondence/notes (1945.37, 1945.138, 1945.454, 1945.580, 1946.51, 1946.159, 1946.179, 1946.293, 1946.294, 1946.296, 1946.299, 1946.300, 1946.345, 1947.99); negatives/transparencies (1945.580, 1946.135, 1946.139, 1946.163, 1946.290).
    - 1947.189 - 1948.115 (Offsite-box 172, Folder -)
      Includes restoration notes (1925.5, 1925.14); correspondence/notes (1947.368, 1947.414a and b, 1947.415, 1947.450, 1947.462, 1947.507, 1947.523, 1948.40 to .42).
    - 1948.122 - 1950.308 (Offsite-box 173, Folder -)
      Includes correspondence/notes (1948.174, 1948.469, 1948.473, 1948.577, 1949.23, 1949.136, 1949.273, 1950.5, 1950.7, 1950.27, 1950.30, 1950.46, 1950.78, 1950.230, 1950.237, 1950.303a-j, 1950.308); negatives/transparencies (1950.27).
    - 1950.309 - 1952.441 (Offsite-box 174, Folder -)
      Includes correspondence/notes (1950.309,1950.311, 1950.333, 1950.335, 1951.9, 1951.76, 1951.80, 1951.444, 1951.466, 1951.468, 1951.475, 1952.80, 1952.82, 1952.84, 1952.289, 1952.335, 1952.381, 1952.425); negatives/transparencies (1951.11, 1951.77, 1952.29, 1952.80).
    - 1953.1 - 1955.297 (Offsite-box 175, Folder -)
      Includes correspondence/notes (1953.63, 1953.71, 1953.101, 1953.185, 1954.39, 1955.172, 1955.275, 1953.238, 1953.318, 1954.39, 1954.57, 1954.177, 1954.197, 1955.96, 1955.97, 1955.98, 1955.172, 1955.275); negatives/transparencies (1953.63, 1953.198, 1953.292, 1955.263).
    - 1955.6 - 1959.19 (Offsite-box 176, Folder -)
      Includes restoration notes (1957.64); correspondence/notes (1956.6, 1956.54, 1956.69, 1956.192, 1957.23, 1957.39, 1957.57, 1957.64, 1957.65, 1957.73, 1957.80, 1957.135, 1957.232, 1957.249, 1957.261, 1958.85, 1958.139, 1959.1 1959.2); negatives/transparencies (1956.145, 1957.52, 1957.64, 1957.97); slide (1957.112, 1957.114). Includes original 1765 declaration of John Cruger naming Joseph Drake a freeman and citizen of New York City (1957.64).
    - 1959.20 - 1968.39 (Offsite-box 177, Folder -)
      Includes correspondence/notes (1960.48, 1961.63, 1962.19, 1961.36, 1962.42, 1962.69, 1962.71, 1962.72, 1962.73, 1962.78, 1963.9, 1963.45, 1964.16, 1966.19, 1966.21, 1966.34, 1966.48, 1966.60, 1966.66); negatives/transparencies (1961.44).
    - 1969.16 a,b - 1982.16 (Offsite-box 178, Folder -)
      Includes restoration notes (1973.36); correspondence/notes (1969.20, 1969.30, 1969.43, 1969.44, 1969.45, 1969.48, 1969.53, 1970.73, 1971.3, 1971.97, 1971.100, 1971.114, 1971.115, 1971.116, 1971.118, 1971.125, 1973.8, 1973.20, 1973.35, 1973.39, 1974.31, 1974.32, 1974.61, 1975.1, 1975.18, 1979.80); transparencies/slides (1969.26, 1970.75, 1971.119, 1973.38, 1973.54 (Van Vorst), 1976.68, 1978.46, 1979.80, 1980.56, 1981.12). Includes gift of unidentified gentleman and lady from Mr. and Mrs. William Middendorf II (1970.72, 1970.73) and gift of Peck portraits from Mrs. Cecil G. Hemsley (1974.29); portrait of Seth Low by Eastman Johnson (1975.18); deed of gift for the Portrait of Mrs. Van Vorst by Mary Foote from Edward Foote (1978.31).
    - 1983.32 - 1985.17 (Offsite-box 179, Folder -)
      Negatives/transparencies/slides (1984.121). Includes gifts from Mr. and Mrs. Stuart Feld (1983.50, 1983.51, 1983.52, 1983.53, 1983.54, 1983.55); gift from Mrs. Rose Newman of Raphael Soyer drawing (1985.17).
    - X.5 - x.521 (Offsite-box 179, Folder -)
      Includes restoration notes (x.5, x.27, x.63); correspondence/notes (x.26, x.63, x.273, x.293, x.515); negatives/transparencies (x.474).
    - L1927.1 - L1972.1 (Offsite-box 179, Folder -)
      Includes correspondence/notes on loans (L1927.1, L1945.3, L1946.1, L1946.2, L1946.6, L1947.5, L1947.8, L1948.4, L1948.5, L1952.1, L1953.2, L1953.5, L1954.1, L1954.5, L1954.6, L1955.1, L1955.2, L1955.7). Includes loan of Lord and Lady Stirling portraits from Goodhue Livingston (L1960.5).
  - Subseries VI.B. Sets of Images, Undated; 15.71 Linear feet
    The subseries includes sets of images representing portions of N-YHS's current or past collections. The subseries currently holds only a few such sets: negatives of the Stuart collection, small (4" x 3") lantern slides of works by American and European artists, and photographs of the Rufus A. Grider powder horns, George Catlin drawings, and Dunsmore drawings.
    In 2019, several trays of slides were transferred to the archives. These appear to be of various objects and of objects in exhibitions. Some slides appear to be reference objects from other institutions.
    - Stuart Collection Negatives (Acetate), Undated (Offsite-box 180, Envelope 1-139)
      Includes acetate negatives, mostly 8x11, of Stuart collection objects. Emails in the box from 2007 suggest that these were scanned and have digital versions.
    - Stuart Collection Negatives (Glass), Undated (Box 181, Folder -)
      Includes ten 8x11 plates: #26, 114, 141, 169, 172, 186, 200, 229, 232, 239.
    - Lantern Slides. American Artists. Alexander to Chapman, Undated (Box 182, Item -)
    - Lantern Slides. American Artists. Child to Durand, Undated (Box 183, Item -)
    - Lantern Slides. American Artists. Durand to Feke, Undated (Box 184, Item -)
    - Lantern Slides. American Artists. Feke to Hesselius, Undated (Box 185, Item -)
    - Lantern Slides. American Artists. Hesselius to Jarvis, Undated (Box 186, Item -)
    - Lantern Slides. American Artists. Jennys to Mount, Undated (Box 187, Item -)
    - Lantern Slides. American Artists. Mount to Robertson, Undated (Box 188, Item -)
    - Lantern Slides. American Artists. Savage to Stuart, Undated (Box 189, Item -)
    - Lantern Slides. American Artists. Stuart to Vanderlyn, Undated (Box 190, Item -)
    - Lantern Slides. American Artists. Vanderlyn to Wright, Undated (Box 191, Item -)
    - Lantern Slides. American Artists. Unknown, Undated (Box 192, Item -)
    - Lantern Slides. American Artists. Unknown; European (Italian, Spanish), Undated (Box 193, Item -)
    - Lantern Slides. European Artists (Dutch, English, Flemish, French, Italian), Undated (Box 194, Item -)
    - Photographs & inventory. Rufus A. Grider Powder Horn Drawings (21 folders), Undated (Offsite-box 275, Folder 1-21)
    - Photographs. Dunsmore Drawings, Undated (Offsite-box 275, Folder 22)
    - Photographs. George Catlin Drawings (8 folders), Circa 1987? (Offsite-box 275, Folder 23-30)
      Includes a report on the Catlin Collection by Curator Ella Foshay.
    - Miscellaneous Slides, undated (Offsite-box 300)
    - Miscellaneous Slides, undated (Offsite-box 301)